JAMES MCCORKINDALE

CONTACT

Glasgow, Milngaive G62 6DX

07482 561740

jamesmccorkindale0@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Great overall tutor and role-model Great communication skills Very quick learner Great problem solving skills Strong leader Very determined Extremely intuitive

CERTIFICATIONS

- ABRSM Grade 8 Guitar

- ABRSM Grade 6 Trombone
 ABRSM Grade 5 Theory
 2 Time winner of Glasgow Music Festival
 (Guitar Solos Open)
 2nd Kyu (Karate)

I am currently in my 6th year at Douglas Academy, studying Advanced Higher Computer Science, Maths and Chemistry.

I have a love for Computer Science and writing software. I am most familiar with C++, Python and the four web-designing languages (HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP). I have worked on several different projects, of all varying sizes, ranging from Desktop applications to setting up this webserver (with a private cloud), hosting on my Rasberry Pi.

EXPERIENCE

June 2018 to Current

Maths and Music Tutoring Self-Employed, Glasgow, East Dumbartonshire

- Created tailored lessons and lesson plans to meet the needs of each student. Created structures to ensure homework, progress and goals were maintained by all
- my pupils. Lessons delivered face to face as well as over online video call.
- Tutored Maths up to SQA Higher level.
- Delivered classical guitar lessons to absolute beginners to a standard of ABRSM Grade 8, in 4 years.
- Delivered music theory lessons to a standard of ABRSM grade 5.
- Tutored music up to SQA Higher level.

August 2021 to Current

Voluntary Work - Computing Club and Silver Surfers Douglas Academy, Glasgow, East Dumbartonshire

- Creating informative videos about basic technology targeted at the older generation who need help.
- Helping young pupils (13-14 y/o) at a computer science club develop their coding and IT skills.

August 2018 to March 2019

Volunteering at Cub Scouts Scouts Organisation, Glasgow, East Dumbartonshire

Supported the Scout Leaders with taking weekly groups of Cub Scouts.

- Provided a positive role model for the Cub Scouts
- Ran and organised games nights, and other activities.

EDUCATION

TMUA (6.8)

Cambridge Assessment Admissions Tests, Cambridge, CAM

SQA Advanced Higher (A Grade) Music Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA Higher (A Grade) Computing Science Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA Higher (A Grade) Maths Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA Higher (A Grade) Chemistry Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA Higher (A Grade) English Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA Higher (A Grade) Music Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA National 5 (A Grade) Computing Science Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA National 5 (A Grade) Maths Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA National 5 (A Grade) Chemistry Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA National 5 (A Grade) English Douglas Academy, East Dunbartonshire

SQA National 5 (A Grade) Geography **Douglas Academy**